原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     冰岛豆腐   Eunice   赛残阳
翻译     青椒   斗斗
校对     冰岛豆腐
时间轴     姜姜
后期     8T
总监     冰岛豆腐
《高玩救未来》前情提要
Previously on Future Man
我不想说出来的
I hate to tell you this
但你玩这游戏有点走火入魔了
but you might have an unhealthy obsession with this video game.
才没有  雷
No, I don't! Ray.
够了  卡米洛博士
That's enough, Dr. Camillo.
抱歉  克罗尼什博士
I'm... I'm sorry, Dr. Kronish.
如果你想继续为我工作
If you want to keep working for me,
就少损人  多擦点尿道
I suggest less tongue-lashing and more urethra-swabbing.
快去擦吧
Now off you go, swab, swab.
住在你儿时的家没有任何问题
And there's nothing weird about living in your childhood home.
这也是我儿时的家  我就住这儿
This is my childhood home and I live here.
这是福特曼的房子
This is a Futterman house.
我们不会杀克罗尼什
We're not killing Kronish!
任务是阻止他染上疱疹
The mission is to stop him from getting herpes,
让他当不成科学家
prevent him from becoming a scientist,
然后他就永远制造不出解药了
and then he never creates the cure.
我比舞胜出了
I won a dance-off.
黑苹果
Black apple?
我是救世主
I'm the savior.
我操
Fuck me.
2162年4月1日
洛杉矶
安全了  人都到齐了吗
Okay, we're clear. Is everyone here?
快速点名
Quick roll call.
猎豹  猫鼬  猎鹰  臭鼬
Cheetah, Mongoose, Falcon, Skunk
鹰  豹  熊  狐狸  海豚  甲虫
Eagle, Panther, Bear, Fox, Dolphin, Beetle
雪貂  短吻鳄  刺猬  黄蜂  野狗  老鼠
Ferret, Alligator, Hedgehog, Wasp, Dingo, Mouse
黄鼠狼  猴子  猩猩  狐猴  驼鹿  土狼
Weasel, Monkey, Gorilla, Lemur, Moose, Coyote
虫子  螳螂  蜘蛛  美洲狮  麝鼠  鬣狗
Worm, Mantis, Spider, Cougar, Muskrat, Hyena
野牛  猫鼬  角马  野猪  豪猪  蝙蝠
Bison, Meerkat, Wildebeest, Boar, Porcupine, Bat
鸷  斑马  地鼠  兔子  狼
Hawk, Zebra, Gopher, Rabbit, and Wolf.
好了
Okay.
时空穿梭装置和通往救世主的路就在这条隧道的那头
Through this tunnel lies the TTD and a path to our savior.
成败在此一役
This is it.
我们是人类最后的希望
We're humanity's last hope.
甚至是你  虫子
Even you, Worm.
你们知道吗
And guess what?
当我们回到2017年
When we get to 2017,
是时候分糖吃了
it's time to share the sugar.
我当然把它带上了
You're God damn right I brought it with me.
我们要把这糖切成45份
We're slicing this bad boy into 45ths.
好了  伙计们
All right, everybody.
跟着我  准备好武器
Follow me. Weapons hot.
暴狼  你准备好了吗
Wolf, you ready?
我们去炸了这地方
Let's blow some shit up.
听我口令
On my lead.
一日抵御者
Resistance now!
终身抵御者
Resistance forever!
热感应线
Thermal wire.
左右喷氯化物
Diametric chloride.
快跑
Run!
别去  别去  别去
No, no, no.
沾气即死
That gas means death.
老鹰
Eagle!
不要啊
No!
快跑
Run!
我不能...该死  这拉链  就像...
I can't... God damn it, this zipper's, like...
坏了一样
messed up.
你能帮我一下吗
Can I get a little help?
卡住了
It's jammed.
看  卡住了
See? It's jammed.
卡住了
It's jammed.
该死的  总是发生在我身上
God damn it! It always happens to me.
高玩救未来
第一季第三集
第三章
时空巨洞
2017年12月12日
洛杉矶
我们为什么要这么做  你不是住在这吗
Why are we doing this, don't you live here?
是的  我住这儿
Yes, I do live here
但我不知道我父母是否在楼下
But I don't know if my parents are downstairs or not
所以我要去确认一下
so I have to go check.
你们就待在这  不要发出声音
You guys just stay here, try not to make any noise
也不要碰任何东西
And then, don't touch anything.
我的手机在哪
Where the fuck is my phone?
-爸妈  -嗨  亲爱的
- Guys. - Hi sweetie.
我  我以为你们在...清理海滩
I-I thought you were doing uh... the-the beach cleanup today.
没错  只不过忘拿我的拨火棍[扑克]
We are, just forgot my poker.
他们喜欢你自带装备
They like it when you bring your own equipment.
看我的"扑克脸"
Check out my "Poker face."
拜托  儿子  这在海滩上可以迷死一片人
Come on, son, that kills down at the beach.
为什么墙上会挂着把枪
Why is there a gun on the wall?
你什么意思  我们家一直有枪啊
What do you mean, we've always had a gun.
这是福特曼的房子
This is a Futterman house.
你还好吗  亲爱的
Are you okay, honey?
我们可以不去海滩
We can cancel.
不用  不用  不用  不用
No, no, no, no!
我...我只是试图想起来
No, I... I was just trying to remember
你是什么时候买的那个经典壁挂的
when did you get that classy wall mount?
这是你爷爷放上去的
That's the same one your grandpa put up.
我只是给它擦了点油
I just gave it a little oil.
爷爷持枪
Grandpa was a gun guy?
在登月之夜家里闯入流氓后
Hard not to be after those hooligans broke in here
很难不去配把枪
the night of the moon landing.
你知道那个故事
You know that story.
三个人
Three of them.
我永远都忘不了他们的脸
I'll never forget their faces.
-你忘不了吗  -几个小个子拉美人
- You won't? - Couple of little Latino fellas.
流浪汉
Vagrants.
其中两个人是流浪汉
Well, two of them were vagrants
第三个是个孩子  看起来很害怕  好像他不想来
Third one was a child, scared, like he didn't want to be there.
总之在那之后  你爷爷去买了伊萨卡37霰弹枪
Anyway, right after that, Grandpa went out and got the old Ithaca 37.
感谢上帝我们没有需要用它的时候
Thank God we never had to use it.
我甚至不知道该怎么用
I'm not even sure how it works.
希望它没有上膛
Hope it's not loaded.
我们该出发了
Hey, we better get going.
拉马尔  到圣塔莫尼卡码头要花多长时间
Lamar, how long is it gonna take to get to Santa Monica Pier?
现在不堵车
The traffic is moderate.
我估计大概40分钟吧
So I'm estimating 40 minutes.
-谢谢  拉马尔  -拉马尔
- Okay, thanks, Lamar. - Lamar?
亲爱的  你不必谢它的
Honey, you don't have to thank it.
不是"它"  是拉马尔·普锐斯
It's not an "It," It's Lamar Price.
不是吧
Oh no.
妈妈  我可以看下...
Hey, Mom, can I see that for just a...
谢谢
Thank you.
黑苹果
Blackapple?
是黑果
It's a Blapple.
只有老年人才会叫它黑苹果
Only old people call it a Blackapple.
这话还是你说的
You told us that.
卧槽
Fuck.
我就是把手机落在那了
That's where I left my phone.
亲爱的  你确定你没事吗
Honey, are you sure that you're okay?
当然  我挺好的
Yeah, yeah, I am, I'm fine.
你们是不是得赶紧走了
Um, you guys should probably get goin'.
走吧  亲爱的  那些带沙子的避孕套
Let's go, honey, those sandy condoms
不会自己飞进垃圾桶的
aren't gonna pick themselves up.
没错  不会的  拜拜啦
Nope, they're not... all right, bye!
拜
Bye!
我们确实改变了一些事
Well, we changed stuff,
但不是我们想改变的...
just not the stuff we want...
我勒个去
Jesus fucking Christ!
你要去哪里
Hey, where are you goin'?
你们不希望我回避一下吗
Do you guys want some privacy?
不用  我们就是充个电
No, we're just chargin' up.
人们干这事的时候一般会选择没人的地方
This is just something that people typically do in private.
为什么
Why?
因为要跟很在乎的人
Because you do it with someone
才能这样做
who means something to you.
-不要停  -好
- Don't stop. - Okay,
那我就靠说话转移注意力吧
I'm just gonna try and talk through this.
所以我们没能阻止克罗尼什得疱疹
Um, so basically we didn't stop Kronish from getting herpes,
但是  我们确实改变了很多事
however, we did change things.
造成了剧烈的蝴蝶效应
Talking major ripples.
蝴蝶效应吗
Ripples?
对  蝴蝶效应
Ripples, ripples.
我们在1969年做的事
What we did in 1969
改变了现在的世界
has had an effect on the present day,
比如我爸现在有一把枪
like my dad now owns a gun,
还有点种族歧视
and is also a little bit racist
现在这玩意叫黑果
and it's probably my fault
估计也是我造成的
that this is now called a blaptop.
求你们停下  好吗
Can you please stop, please?
不行  我还没充满电
I can't, I'm not fully charged yet.
充什么电
Charged for what?
这是释放压力的标准步骤
It's a standard operating procedure to release tension.
左边向下两毫米
Two micrometers down to the left.
干得漂亮  士兵
Nice work, soldier.
即将满电  三  二  一
Fully charged in three, two, one.
太棒了  士兵
Yeah, fuck yeah, soldier!
要的就是这种状态
That is how you perform!
太好了  爽
Yes, fuck yes!
好的  压力释放完毕
All right, tension released.
准备杀敌
Ready to kill.
杀敌  杀谁
Kill, what?
克罗尼什
Kronish.
我们别无选择
It's our only option.
试过你的办法  但是失败了
We tried it your way and we failed.
惨败
Miserably.
不  不行  不能杀克罗尼什
No, no, no, no, you can't murder Kronish,
他现在还没有犯错
he hasn't done anything wrong yet.
《少数派报告》说的就是这个
That's the whole point of Minority Report.
我没听过这个报告
I'm unfamiliar with that report.
你需要我提醒你这件事的重要性吗
Do you need to be reminded of what's at stake here?
他创造了这些变异人
He's the father of these mutants.
你看着这些难道不生气吗
How can you look at that and not feel outrage?
还有  你怎么会有这个生化人玩偶
Also, why the fuck do you even have this tiny Biotic?
你是要救一个人  还是全人类
This is one man versus the fate of humanity.
我们要去实验室  然后杀掉克罗尼什
We're going to the lab and we kill Kronish.
等等  杀一个人要这么多武器吗
Whoa, you... you need all of that to kill one man?
很显然  在杀他之前
Well, obviously a lot of other people are gonna die
还得死很多人
to get to that one man.
战争牺牲品
Casualties of war.
他们死总比我们死强
Better them than us.
你也知道这是唯一的办法
You know this is the only way.
不  肯定还有其他办法
No, no, there has to be another way.
他们不是生化人
These are not Biotics.
他们是我的同事
These are people that I work with.
你能让我们靠近他吗
Can you get us close to him?
如果你能隔离他
If you can isolate him,
那其他人就没必要受伤了
then no one else has to get hurt.
抱歉  身为救世主并不代表你能救所有人
Sorry, being the savior doesn't mean you get to save everyone.
你能让我们进那栋大楼吗
Can you get us in the building?
悄悄进去肯定是不行的
Not without creating a huge scene.
而且有三层安保
And there's three layers of security.
我有工作证  都只能通过其中两层
I've got a badge and I can only get through two.
好吧  那你的任务很简单
Okay, then your job is simple.
把克罗尼什引出来
You just need to lure Kronish out there
然后我们杀他时你看不看都行
and then it's up to you whether you watch us kill him.
你应该看看
Oh, you should watch.
我们会把他变成一滩内脏
We're gonna turn him into a puddle of guts.
进去吧  别让抵御者失望  未来侠
Now go in there and make the Resistance proud, future Man.
这个计划不好  猎虎
This is a bad plan, Tiger.
我的感应雷足够炸倒这座大楼
I got enough sensor mines to drop this building.
你看他们的防护多弱
Look how weak those defenses are.
比如  护城壕沟在哪
I mean, where's the moat?
看到有放射性水陆两用车吗
You see any radioactive alligators?
-我是没看到  -不行  必须确保他死掉
- I don't. - No, we need a confirmed kill.
我穿越时空过来
I didn't travel through time
不是为了翻尸体堆找人的
to keep picking through piles of rubble for body parts.
准备就位吧
Now let's get into position.
未来侠大概还有
Future Man should be out in...
不到三根手指就出来了
less than three fingers.
走吧
Let's go.
好的
All right.
早上好  乔西
Morning, Josh.
卡尔  你好
Hey Carl, hey...
等等  雷去哪儿了
Hey, wait, where... where's Ray?
雷是谁
Who's Ray?
操  我把雷给弄没了
Fuck, I made Ray disappear.
该死的蝴蝶效应
God damn ripples.
有什么事吗
Um, can I help you?
请问  克罗尼什在里面吗
Yeah, is... is Kronish in there?
他不在卡米洛博士的办公室
Well, he's not in Dr. Camillo's office, no.
斯图·卡米洛博士
他们还在吃合伙人早餐
They're still at their partners' breakfast.
合伙人  我是怎么做到的
Partners, how the fuck did I do that?
你做到了什么
How did you do what?
抱歉  你还好吗
Sorry, are you okay?
没事  就是...
Yeah, it's just...
你有没有哪天醒来
uh, have you ever had one of those days
觉得整个世界都很熟悉
where you wake up and the whole world is recognizable,
但是又完全不一样呢
but also really different?
你是说《怪诞星期五》那种呢
Mm, you mean like in Freaky Friday
还是《黑客帝国》那种
or a Matrix-type situation?
都不是  比较像是《回到未来》的结尾
No, more like the end of Back to the Future.
懂了  就是说平行现实
Oh, so it's like an alternate reality.
发现父母特别酷
Your parents are super cool,
而自家车库里突然多出一辆很酷的车吗
and all of a sudden you have this awesome new truck in your garage?
大概吧  或者说史蒂夫·乔布斯不存在
Sort of, or, like, Steve Jobs doesn't exist.
谁
Who?
你看
Exactly.
你觉不觉得那部电影严重忽略了
Don't you think that movie, like, really undersold
如果马蒂回到一个
how hard it would have been
他从没过过的生活该有多难吗
for Marty to come back to a life that he never lived?
我从来没那么想过
Guess I never thought about it like that.
我只是很想要那台芭比悬浮滑板
I just really wanted that Barbie Hoverport.
天啊
Oh my God.
真的很想要
Really wanted it.
他余生每一次交谈
He would have to fake his way
都得伪装演戏
through every conversation for the rest of his life.
算你走运
Well, lucky for you this is actually
这其实是我们第一次交谈
the first conversation that we've ever had,
所以你不用假装什么
so you don't have to fake your way through this.
也对
Uh, yeah.
对了  我是乔西
Uh, I'm Josh, by the way.
我知道
I know.
真的吗
You do?
求你了  斯图  别逼我做这个
Please, Stu, I beg you, don't make me do this.
这些焦点小组可能会很羞辱人
These... these focus groups can be humiliating.
振作一点  伊莱亚斯  这对公司有好处
Buck up, Elias, it's good for the company.
除非你不是以公司为重的人
Unless you're not a company man.
我当然是  斯图  但你知道我从来不爱出风头
I am, Stu, but you know I've never been a showman.
我  我讨厌成为别人关注的焦点
I... I hate being the center of attention.
你才不会成为别人关注的焦点
You're not gonna be the center of attention.
你嘴唇上那坨迷你千层面才会
That little mini lasagna on your lip is.
你看什么看  白痴
What are you looking at, butthead?
你的机会来了
There's your Biff.
对
Uh, yeah.
克罗尼什博士
Dr. Kronish,
我能问你个问题吗
can I ask you a question?
你到底是怎么染上疱疹的
How in the hell did you get herpes?
一切要从登月那晚说起
Well, it started the night of the moon landing.
输了一场斗舞让我当众蒙羞后
Being totally humiliated after losing a dance-off,
我立刻从兄弟会逃走
I was summarily run out of my fraternity.
我试着重拾自信
I tried to regain my confidence
踏上了遍布世界的性爱征程
by embarking on a sexual odyssey across several continents,
并且
and, well...
"上"了数不清的炮友
countless partners.
我很肯定就是这样染上疱疹的
I'm pretty sure that's how I got herpes.
好吧
Yeah.
克罗尼什博士  我...
Um, Dr. Kronish, I, uh,
我要带你出去看样东西
I need to show you something outside.
是什么
What is it?
是惊喜
It's a surprise.
我可喜欢惊喜了
Ooh, I love surprises.
太好了  你愿意跟我来吗
Great, you want to come with me?
我问你个事
Uh, look, let me ask you something.
你要带我去的那个地方冷吗
Will it be chilly where you're taking me?
挺冷的
Pretty chilly.
我们要去很久吗
Will we be gone long?
很久
Yeah, a long time.
等等  停一下
Stop, stop what you're doing.
我做不到
I... I can't do this.
把外套脱掉
Take... take off your coat.
到底要怎么样
What's it gonna be?
你有生命危险  知道吗
Your life is in danger, okay?
到底穿不穿外套
So coat or no coat?
不  听我说  克罗尼什博士
No, listen to me, Dr. Kronish.
有人想要你的命
There are people who want you dead.
你得离开这里  你得躲起来
You have to get out of here, you have to hide.
我保护不了你
I can't protect you.
你是在说支持动物权利的那些人吧
Oh, you're talking about those animal rights people.
他们已经揪着我好几年了
They've been after me for years.
我已经收到过将近两万次死亡威胁了
I must be nearing 20,000 death threats.
真的吗
Really?
你知道我们每年在这儿
Do you have any idea how many possums we kill
杀死多少只负鼠吗
at this facility annually?
数量惊人
Staggering numbers.
不  克罗尼什博士  这严重多了
No, Dr. Kronish, this is much worse.
这些人是训练有素的杀手
These people are trained killers,
他们不喜欢你
and they don't like you,
也不喜欢你的研究
and they don't like your research,
他们会竭尽所能
and they'll do anything they can
阻止研究成果流出市面
to prevent it from getting out there.
你必须躲起来
You have to disappear.
我绝不能那样做  福特曼
I could never do that, Futterman.
我的研究太重要了
My work is too important.
如果你死了
What good is your work...
你的研究还有什么用
if you're dead?
我感激你对我的关心
I appreciate your concern.
如果你那么担心的话
And if you're all that worried,
打这个电话
Call that number.
他们专门处理死亡威胁
They handle all my death threats.
找卡罗尔
Ask for Carol.
已经过了六根半手指了
It's been, like, six and a half fingers.
我们都知道救世主不会来了
We both know the savior's not coming.
不如直接把这栋楼给炸了吧
Let's just blow up the building.
不行
No.
我们得亲自动手
We're gonna have to do this ourselves.
当面杀了他
Up close and personal.
好了各位  我们现在要进去参加焦点小组了
Okay everybody! We're gonna go inside now for the focus group.
请在这儿排成一直线
So please form a single file line right here.
机会来了
Ratpot.
克罗尼什实验室
你  排成这队形是要干什么
You. What is the nature of this formation?
我们是来参加焦点小组的
We're here for the focus group.
你没拿这传单吗
Didn't you get one of these?
运气太好了  克罗尼什
Double ratpot. Kronish!
伊莱亚斯·克罗尼什博士亲临现场
弗利特伍德麦克乐队
Fleetwood Mac.
到后面排队
Back of the line.
你活得不耐烦了吗  小丑
You want to bleed, jester?
到后面排队
Back of the line.
算了
Save it.
低调一点
Low profile.
会长在口腔  生殖器  甚至肛门上
Oral, genital, even anal,
他们称之为单纯疱疹病毒
they call it herpes simplex,
但它一点不单纯
but there's nothing simple about it.
我是伊莱亚斯·克罗尼什博士
Um, I'm Dr. Elias Kronish,
我在为你们寻找解药
and I'm seeking the cure for you...
也为我自己
and for me.
有什么想法和感受吗
Thoughts, feelings?
已经连续第三遍了
That's the third one of these in a row.
我再也受不了了  我们已经进来了
I can't take it anymore... we're in the building,
-直接去找那个混蛋  把他灭了吧  -不行
- let's just go find the motherfucker and kill him. - No.
看这段视频让我不自在
Watching it made me uncomfortable,
可能是因为他也很不自在
I think because he was uncomfortable.
克罗尼什会来的  辛迪保证过的
Kronish will be here, Cindy promised.
我不信任辛迪
I don't trust Cindy.
她表面在笑  但她眼神很悲伤
She's smiling, but she has sad eyes.
对哦
Oh yeah.
还有其他人对克罗尼什博士有感想吗
Anyone else have thoughts on Dr. Kronish?
我鄙视他和他所拥护的一切
I despise him and everything he stands for.
你已经是第三次这么说了  知道了
That's the third time you've said that, noted.
他要是死了我还喜欢他多一点
I'd like him better if he died.
好吧
Okay.
还有其他人想看到克罗尼什博士死吗
Anyone else want to see Dr. Kronish die?
有
Yes.
这个嘛
Well...
你说过克罗尼什博士会来的
You said Kronish was gonna be here.
他人呢  辛迪
Where is he, Cindy?
我说过了  克罗尼什博士很忙
Again, Dr. Kronish is very busy.
不如我们来看下一条宣传片
Why don't we take a look at our next ad?
事先说明一下
Just want to say in advance,
在本片制作过程中  没有负鼠受伤
no possums were hurt in the making of this.
你们刚听到的声音
The sound you just heard
是负鼠射精的声音
is a possum ejaculating.
不如我们炸了这该死的大楼
Let's just blow up the fucking building.
干掉克罗尼什和剩下的这堆垃圾
Take out Kronish and the rest of this trash.
好  我只需要大家填完这个表格
Okay, I'm just gonna have you all fill out this form.
这真他妈操蛋
This is some fucking shit.
我们已经进来了  直接去干掉他吧
You know, we're in the building, let's just go.
好主意  指挥官
Brilliant idea, commander.
暴狼
Wolf.
不不不  谁也不能走
Oh, no, no, no. No one leaves.
真的吗
Really?
你要阻止我们吗  辛迪
You're gonna stop us, Cindy?
你真想这么干吗
You want to do that?
他们去哪儿了
Where did they go?
操
Shit.
-怎么了  -他们说好会
- What happened? - They promised they'd do a better job
更仔细检查来这里的人的
screening who comes to these things.
不要啊
Oh no.
他们去哪儿了
Where'd they go?
快弄出来
Get it out!
-杰莉  -乔西
- Geri. - Josh.
你你你要去哪儿
What... where are you going?
你要去哪儿
Where are you going?
我在找两个人
I'm looking for two people.
我也是  我在找史密斯博士和阿珀英格博士
Yeah, so am I, Dr. Smith and Dr. Apoyngo.
他们失踪了吗
Have they gone missing?
没失踪  只是演示迟到了
Missing, no, they're just late for a demo.
他们在三楼是吧
Okay, they're on three, right?
-对  -好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
不要死啊  阿珀英格
Oh, don't be dead, Apoyngo.
不要死啊  阿珀英格  不要死啊  阿珀英格
Don't be dead, Apoyngo, don't be dead, Apoyngo.
不要死啊  阿珀英格
Don't be dead, Apoyngo.
救命  我们在这里
Help! We're in here!
出什么事了
What happened?
很高兴见到你
Good to greet you.
我们偷的这两件白大褂的主人没有
Those whitecoats we stole from don't have access
进入内部密室的权限
to the inner sanctum.
我们另找方法进去
We'll find another way in.
暴狼博士
Dr. Wolf.
相信我  克罗尼什在楼上
I'm telling you, Kronish is upstairs.
高价值目标总是藏在地下掩体里
High value targets are always in the subterranean bunkers.
我觉得这里不是这么回事
I don't think it works that way here.
你的工作不是思考
It's not your job to think,
你的工作是听从我的命令
it's your job to take orders from me.
这地方的防御不堪一击
This place isn't built for defense.
这是我见过的第一件武器
This is the first weapon I've seen,
还是挂在墙上当装饰品的
and it's mounted on the wall for decoration.
-猎虎  我的直觉...  -去你的直觉
- Tiger, my instincts... - Fuck your instincts.
沃多的宫殿里沃多在哪儿
Valdor's Palace, where was Valdor?
在地下的墓穴里
In the underground catacombs.
古丽加神庙里古丽加在哪儿
Temple of Gooliga, where was Gooliga?
在古丽加府邸
In the Gooligorium.
府邸在哪儿呢
And where is that?
在地心旁边
By the earth's core.
没有比那更地下的了
Doesn't get more underground than that,
是不是啊  小暴狼
now does it, Wolfie?
天啊
Jesus.
相信我
Trust me.
克罗尼什就在这
This is the way to Kronish.
我操
Oh, f...
该死的
Goddammit.
暴狼
Wolf.
自打第一天起你他妈的就瞧不起我
You've been underestimating me since day fucking one.
我有想法
I have ideas,
有的想法还挺不错的
some of 'em are even good.
我策划的任务
I planned a mission
然后出了岔子
and then it went sideways.
再然后就乱套了
Then it went upside down.
我现在在盲飞[凭着自己的感觉]
I am flying blind,
不仅斜着还是颠倒的
sideways, and upside down,
你就不能让我消停会儿
so give me a fucking break.
但你不是一个人在战斗
But you're not doin' it alone.
我们突破血门的时候
When we busted through the Blood Gates,
是谁在边上支持你
who was by your side?
他们在阿拉默死地放火烧我们时
When they set us on fire in the Death Fields of Alamore,
是谁找到了污水池  我们才得以逃脱的
who found that sewage reservoir for us to jump into?
当眼镜蛇叛变
When Cobra turned
试图趁你睡觉给你下毒时
and tried to poison you in your sleep...
是谁拧下了那叛徒的脑袋
...who pulled that fuckin' traitor's head off?
是猫鼬
Mongoose.
不
No.
是暴狼
Wolf.
我把自己的命交给你
I've given you my life
因为我信任你
because I trust you,
你好歹也偶尔听听我的建议
and the least you can do is just listen to me once in a while.
好吧
Okay.
下一步怎么办  士兵
What's our next move, soldier?
我们再冲回去
So we blast back in there,
找到克罗尼什在哪间办公室
find which office Kronish is in,
到那边屋顶上
post up on that roof,
用狙击声波干掉他
and take him out with a Sniper Sonic.
声波会穿透玻璃
The sound waves will pass right through the glass
直接爆掉他的脑袋
and just pop his fuckin' head off.
干净漂亮
Nice and clean.
好了
All right.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
天啊  别开枪
Oh, God, don't shoot!
-该死的混蛋  -搞什么呢  哥们
- Fuckin' dick. - What the fuck, buddy.
你俩脑子有什么毛病啊
What the fuck got into you people?
克罗尼什在哪儿
Where's Kronish?
你十根手指前就该到这儿了
You were supposed to be here ten fingers ago.
他没抓到他  我就知道
He doesn't have him... I knew it.
该死的放弃了任务
Fuckin' aborted the mission.
不  你可说不好
No, you don't know that.
或许他只是找不到他
Maybe he just couldn't find him.
不  暴狼说得对  我...我放弃了
No, yeah, Wolf's right, i... I aborted.
-该死  未来侠  -操你妈的
- Goddammit, Future Man. - God fucking...
不
No!
我站到他的面前
I... I got there in front of him,
看着他的眼睛
and I looked into his eyes, and...
我就是下不去手  好吗
I just couldn't do it, okay?
我跟你们不一样  我不是杀人犯
I'm not like you guys, I'm not a murderer.
我们也不是杀人犯
We aren't murderers either.
我们是士兵
We're soldiers.
你以为我们喜欢杀人吗
You think we like killing people?
-看着挺喜欢的  -我们不喜欢
- You sure seem to. - Well, we don't.
我们杀人是出于无奈  不是出于...爱好
We kill because we have to, not because we... we like it.
那个...
Well...
而且这会带来负面影响  知道吗
And it takes a toll, okay?
我睡觉的时候会尖叫
I scream in my sleep.
但我们的感觉不重要  因为我们在执行任务
But our feelings don't matter 'cause we're on a mission,
所以除非你能给我一个战略性理由
so unless you can give me one strategic reason
不杀此人
not to kill this man,
我们就别无选择
we have no choice.
好吧  要是...要是我进去
Okay, what if... what if I went in there
找他谈话  得到了理由呢
and talked to him, and I got you one?
一个饶他一命的理由
A reason not to kill him?
你能做到吗
You could do that?
是的  应该可以
Yeah, I... I think so.
你可以进入地下室
Yeah, you could go in there to the basement
找到我们所需要知道的吗
and find out what we need to know?
地下室  他在顶楼
Basement... he's... he's in the top floor.
棒
Yes!
-好  -好的
- All right. - Okay.
-好  -我这就去
- Okay. - I'm on it.
我们在这儿等你  未来侠
All right, we'll be waiting for you, Future Man.
好
Okay.
你演的哪出戏
What the fuck was that?
我经常看你睡觉
I watch you sleep.
你从没尖叫过
You've never screamed once.
我在他身上放了追踪器
I planted a tracker on him.
他会带我们找到克罗尼什
He'll lead us right to Kronish.
克罗尼什博士
Dr. Kronish!
你得放弃你所有的研究
You need to abandon all of your research.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
今天是具有历史意义的一天
This is an historic day.
你激励了我去做意见我想做了很多年的事
You inspired me to do something I've been wanting to do for years.
你做了什么
What did you do?
你之前让我开始思考
You really got me thinking earlier.
我也许不是刺客的目标
I may not be in the assassin's crosshairs,
但我年纪不小了
but I'm not a young man.
随时可能挂掉
I could go any day.
危机四伏
Danger's all around me.
我不明白
I don't understand.
疱疹的解药不该是我们获利的途径
The cure for herpes shouldn't be ours to profit from.
应该供全世界享用
It should be the world's to heal by.
所以我公开了我的研究
So, I've made all my research public,
分享给了全球的同事
shared it with a global network of colleagues.
你把解药公诸于世了
You put the cure out to the world?
集合全球科学家的智慧
With the combined brainpower of the global scientific community,
疱疹的解药将不会是我的创造
the cure for herpes won't be my creation,
而是我们所有人的
it'll be all of ours.
所以从战略上讲
So strategically speaking,
如果有人想阻止解药面世
uh, if somebody wanted to stop the cure from ever existing,
杀了你也无济于事
murdering you would have zero effect?
疱疹的解药还是会流出
The cure for herpes would still get out there?
这么比喻有点病态  不过是的
A morbid way to put it, but yes.
多亏了你
And thanks to you.
解药可以来自于法国  尼日利亚
Oh, well, the cure could come from France, Nigeria,
西班牙  中国  任何地方
Spain, China, literally from anywhere.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
这真是好消息
That's amazing news.
你可以活命了
You get to live!
卡米洛博士不会高兴的
Dr. Camillo won't be happy.
我捐献出了
I've, uh, I've given away
不少专利材料
quite a bit of proprietary material.
但感觉很棒
But it feels good.
这是很久以来第一次
For the first time in a long time,
我感觉自己还活着
I feel alive!
未来想试图给我们打信号
Future Man's trying to signal us.
叫他让开
Signal to him to get out of the way.
-搞什么  -让开
- What the fuck? - Out of the fucking way.
鸣枪警告一下
Fire a warning shot.
-什么情况  -靠
- What the fuck? - Oh, shit!
-我们得  这里  -那东西
- We gotta... here! - That thing went...
我们可以躲在后面
We can hide behind it, okay?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
他在干什么
What the fuck is he doing?
快躲到这后面  躲进去
Here, hide, go, go. Get behind this. Get behind this one.
他在保护克罗尼什
He protecting Kronish.
你得把他也杀了
You're gonna have to kill him too.
我得带你离开这里
I have to get you out of this building, okay?
什么
What's going...
操
Oh, shit!
你在
What are you...
什么鬼
What the hell?
你想玩游戏
Okay, you want to play games?
你在干什么  福特曼
What are you doing? Futterman!
你什么毛病
What the hell is wrong with you?
调到热成像镜头
Switching to thermal.
你搞什么  你去哪
What the hell? Where are you...
我们得马上离开这  好吗
We have to get out of here right now. Okay?
瞄准克罗尼什了
I've got Kronish.
开枪
Take the shot.
-快走  -放开我
- Go, go, go! - Get your hands off of me!
该上西天了  死亡博士
Time to die, Dr. Death.
-你哪根筋不对  -快走
- What the shit are you into? - Go, go, go, go, go.
刚才怎么回事
What... what was that shit about?
你他妈在想什么  伊莱亚斯
What the fuck were you thinking, Elias?
-你知道你做了什么吗  -斯图
- Do you know what you've done? - Stu!
你毁了这公司  你害死了我们全部
You have buried this company. You have killed us all.
斯图  斯图
Now, Stu, Stu,
这都是在为人类做贡献
it was all about doing right by humanity.
-去他妈的人类  -这样吧
- Fuck humanity. - Okay, you know what?
你们慢慢谈  离窗户远点  知道吗
You guys just hash this out, stay away from windows, okay?
再见
All right, bye.
什么情况
What the fuck?
那些是生化人吗
Are those Biotics?
背捅
Back stab!
前绕
Reach around.
指两人做爱  后面那人给前面那人打飞机
安全
Clear!
Clear.
他们在这儿干什么
What... what... what are they doing here?
他们找到我们只是时间问题
It was only a matter of time before they found us.
我的天
Oh my God.
我的天  这些是真的生化人
Oh my God, they... these are real life Biotics.
曾是生化人
They were Biotics.
他们在现实生活中更恶心
They're even more grosser in real life.
是啊
Oh yeah.
没错  你还从没见过
That's right, you've never seen one.
-是的  -近距离见过
- No. - Up close and personal.
看看这怪物
Yeah, well. Take a look at this monster.
等等  这是卡尔
Wait, that's Carl.
他是这儿的保安
He's a security guard here.
卡尔是生化人
Yeah, well, Carl's a fuckin' Biotic.
可他在这工作多年了
But he's worked here for years.
他是我的秘密圣诞老人
He's my Secret Santa.
他送了我一台iPod Shuffle
He gave me an iPod Shuffle.
-他是人类  -是啊
- He's human. - Yeah.
生化人也是人
Biotics are human.
看
See?
那是财务部的  叫什么来着
But that... that's what's-her-name from Accounting.
我认识这些人
I know these people,
我和他们一起工作
I... I work with them.
当然了
Of course you do.
生化人可以是任何人
Biotics can be anybody.
所以这一切才这么操蛋
That's what makes this so fucked up.